

### **PROFESSIONAL BACKGROUND**

I am a graduate of Computer Systems Engineering, in degree procedures, with experience in desktop applications development with Java and web applications development with the Django framework and other technologies.

I have been working with Java, focused on Desktop Applications, using the following technologies: Java SE and Mayen.

Web skills: JavaScript, PHP, HTML5, Bootstrap 5.

#### **IVAN CASTAÑEDA CONTRERAS**

# **SKILLS AND TOOLS**



ivan.c.contreras@accenture.com



**Application Development Associate - CL12** 



CDMX, México.

- **JSE**, Java 8
- XAMPP
- Cloudinary
- Git

- Maven
- Heroku
- Netbeans
- Intellij IDEA

- · Visual Studio Code
- Firebase
- MySQL Workbench
- · Project Libre

#### **SELECTED RECENT EXPERIENCES**

### JULY 2021-JULY 2021 | ACCENTURE | CDMX

- I'm taking a Java BackEnd Academy at Accenture, in remote mode.
- In this academy I am learning new subjects and reinforcing my Java knowledge.
- During the academy I have done Testing exercises in Java, Java SE and I learned to program in functional java.
- Link: <u>Civan98/AcademiaBackEndJavaCDMXAccenture</u>: <u>En este repositorio se subirán los ejercicios semanales de la Academia Java CDMX Accenture</u>.
  (github.com)

### OCTOBER 2020-JANUARY 2021 | CAPAMA | ACAPULCO, GRO

- During my professional residencies I developed a web application with Django together with two other colleagues, using GitHub for version control, it is an administrative site to attend the reports that users make to report water problems.
- I was responsible for displaying the page in Heroku and performing some backend functions such as login and creation of the database model.
- Link: CAPAMA| servicio de agua potable y saneamiento de Acapulco, Guerrero. (capamaappweb.herokuapp.com)

## SEPTEMBER 2020-NOVEMBER 2020 | INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE ACAPULCO | ACAPULCO, GRO

- I developed code in PHP for a web application of the institute where I studied.
- It is a website where folios are requested and approved for various school settings, it has a CRUD of users, an administrative control panel and PDF reports of the authorized folios can be made.
- Link: TecNM | Tecnológico Nacional de México Campus Acapulco

